Guide to the Duke University Press Records, 1812-1991
Duke University. University Archives
Duke University Press records 1812-1991
Duke University. University Archives
Duke University Press
14.7 linear feet Extent: approximately 10,000 Items
Duke University Press publishes both scholarly books and journals, primarily in the humanities and social sciences. In its early years, preference was given to works published by faculty, graduate students and alumni and to works focused on southern states. The records of Duke University Press span from 1812-1991 and consist of correspondence, annual catalogs, advertisements, annual reports, Board minutes, contracts and agreements, book and journal reviews, financial records and facsimiles of the Carlyle letters.
UA.07.08.0002
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Duke University Press Records were received by the University Archives as a series of transfers from 1956-1993, 2010.
Historical Note
The origins of Duke University Press date back to 1892 and the establishment of the Trinity College Historical Society. In 1921, the Trinity College Press was officially founded. William T. Laprade served as the first Director until 1926. That same year, Duke University Press was founded with William K. Boyd as Director. Following Boyd as Director were the following: Paul F. Baum (1927-1930), J. Fred Rippy (1930-1936), Henry Dwire (1936-1944), Laprade (1944-1951), Ashbel G. Brice (1951-1981), Richard C. Rowson (1981-1989), Lawrence J. Malley (1989-1993), and Stanley Fish (1993-1998).
Duke University Press publishes approximately 120 books annually and more than 30 journals. It publishes primarily in the humanities and social sciences and issues a few publications for primarily professional audiences (e.g., in law or medicine). It is best known for its publications in the broad and interdisciplinary area of theory and history of cultural production.
Collection Overview
The records are arranged in the following series: Director's files, Editorial Advisory Board, Editorial files, Author files, Subject files, Financial records, Catalogs, the Association of American University Presses and the Carlyle Letters. The collection consists of correspondence, annual catalogs, advertisements, Board minutes, annual reports, contracts and agreements, book and journal reviews, financial records and facsimiles of the Carlyle letters. The material ranges in date from 1812-1991.
Subject Headings
Duke University -- History -- 20th century; Duke University Press; Laprade, William Thomas, 1873-1975; Dwire, Henry R.; Rippy, J. Fred (James Fred), 1892-1977; Rhine, J. B. (Joseph Banks), 1895-1980; Carlyle, Thomas, 1795-1881; Carlyle, Jane Welsh, 1801-1866; Association of American University Presses; Journals, Scholarly; Journals (Periodicals); Hispanic American Historical Review.; Ecological Monographs.; Brice, Ashbel
Related Material
Bernard I. Duffey Papers, 1957-1983
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library/University Archives, Duke University
South Atlantic Quarterly Records, 1926-1986
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library/University Archives, Duke University
William Thomas Laprade Papers, 1660-1975 (bulk 1898-1975)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library/University Archives, Duke University
Henry R. Dwire Papers, 1897-1944
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library/University Archives, Duke University
Thomas Carlyle Papers, 1809-1927 and undated.
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library at Duke University
Jane Welsh Carlyle-Henrietta Stanley letters, 1852-1865
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library at Duke University
Contents of Collection
- Director Files, 1932-1990
  This series consists primarily of the Director's correspondence. Unlike other series, the Director's files are arranged by accession due primarily to the presence of two very different periods of time.
  Accession A56-699 contains correspondence from 1932-1957, covering the tenures of J. Fred Rippy (1930-1936) and Henry Dwire (1936-1944), and W. T. Laprade (1944-1951). Both Dwire and Laprade were named Acting Director while also serving as Editor of the South Atlantic Quarterly, a journal published by the Press. The correspondence for this period covers both the Press and the SAQ. Overall, the correspondence focuses primarily on getting books to press and requests to publish books/articles. Correspondents include Clement Eaton, J. B. Rhine, and Daniel C. Roper. Of particular interest is the correspondence during the 1940s, showing how the Press handled the cutbacks and financial burdens of the war years.
  Accession A93-54 contains subject files during the 1980s. Subjects include American Literature journal, budget, staff memos, and Friends of the Press.
  - Director's Files, 1932-1936 (Box 1)
  - Director's Files, 1937 (Box 1)
  - Director's Files, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Director's Files, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Director's Files, 1940 January-July (Box 1)
  - Director's Files, 1940 August-December (Box 1)
  - Director's Files, 1941 January-July (Box 1)
  - Director's Files, 1941 August-December (Box 1)
  - Director's Files, 1942 January-April (Box 1)
  - Director's Files, 1942 May-August (Box 1)
  - Director's Files, 1942 September-December (Box 1)
  - Director's Files, 1943 January-June (Box 1)
  - Director's Files, 1943 July-December (Box 1)
  - Director's Files, 1943-1948 (Folklore Collection) (Box 1)
  - Director's Files, 1944 January-June (Box 1)
  - Director's Files, 1944 July-December (Box 1)
  - Director's Files, 1945 (Box 1)
  - Director's Files, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Director's Files, 1947 January-May (Box 2)
  - Director's Files, 1947 June-December (Box 2)
  - Director's Files, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Director's Files, 1949 (Box 2)
  - Director's Files, 1950 January-June (Box 2)
  - Director's Files, 1950 July-December (Box 2)
  - Director's Files, 1951 January-June (Box 2)
  - Director's Files, 1951 July-December (Box 2)
  - Director's Files, 1952 January-June (Box 2)
  - Director's Files, 1952 July-December (Box 2)
  - Director's Files, 1953 January-June (Box 2)
  - Director's Files, 1953 July-December (Box 2)
  - Director's Files, 1954 January-June (Box 2)
  - Director's Files, 1954 July-December (Box 2)
  - Director's Files, 1955 January-June (Box 2)
  - Director's Files, 1955 July-December (Box 2)
  - Director's Files, 1956 January-June (Box 2)
  - Director's Files, 1956 July-December (Box 2)
  - Director's Files, 1957 January-September (Box 2)
  - Director's Files, undated (Box 2)
  - Director's Files, 1941-1942 (Reports/Contracts) (Box 2)
  - Director's Files, American Literature, 1986-1988 (Box 3)
  - Director's Files, Budget, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Director's Files, Budget Review Meeting w/ University Officers, 20 March 1986 (Box 3)
  - Director's Files, Committee on the Future of the South Atlantic Quarterly (Box 3)
  - Director's Files, In-house Computers, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Director's Files, Meeting w/ Dick Stubbing, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Director's Files, Report to the Chancellor, 1978 (Box 3)
  - Director's Files, Special Projects Request, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Director's Files, Staff memos, 1981-1984 (Box 3)
  - Director's Files, Joanne Ferguson, 1984-1989 (Box 3)
  - Director's Files, Susan Kuc, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Director's Files, John Menapace, 1981-1984 (Box 3)
  - Director's Files, Jim Roberts, 1985-1988 (Box 3)
  - Director's Files, Daniel J.J. Ross, 1984-1989 (Box 3)
  - Welty, Eudora (Box 3)
  - Friends of the Press, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Friends of the Press, i.e. Board of Visitors, Editorial Advisory Board, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Friends of the Press, 1989-1990 (Box 3)
- Editorial Advisory Board, 1939-1991
  Records included in this series are minutes, correspondence and subject files of the Editorial Advisory Board of the Press. The Board was established by an action of the University Trustees in 1926. Original responsibilities included selecting the Director, approving budgets, giving final approval on manuscripts, advising on staffing, establishing policies, and supervising periodical publications.
  Some discrepancies on the exact title of the Board can be seen throughout this series. The Board was established as the Editorial and Administrative Board and is also referred to as the Duke Press Board. Moreover, the Board has also been considered a standing University committee.
  - Editorial Advisory Board, 1944-1953 (Box 3)
  - Editorial Advisory Board, 1954-1955 Spring (Box 3)
  - Editorial Advisory Board, 1955 October-1956 Spring (Box 3)
  - Editorial Advisory Board, 1956 December-1957 Spring (Box 3)
  - Editorial Advisory Board, 1957 October 1, Meeting (Box 3)
  - Editorial Advisory Board, 1958 February-May (Box 3)
  - Editorial Advisory Board, 1958 October-November (Box 3)
  - Editorial Advisory Board, 1959 March-1960 December (Box 3)
  - Editorial Advisory Board, 1971 May-1974 June (Box 3)
  - Editorial Advisory Board, 1980 March 19-1987 March 23 (Box 3)
  - Editorial Advisory Board, 1987 April 27-1989 November 27 (Box 3)
  - Editorial Advisory Board, 1984-1989 (Duplicates) (Box 3)
  - Editorial Advisory Board, Chairman's Files, 1960-1962 (Box 3)
  - Editorial Advisory Board, Chairman's Files, 1962-1963 (Box 3)
  - Editorial Advisory Board, Chairman's Files, 1962-1964 (Box 3)
  - Editorial Advisory Board, Chairman's Files, 1964-1966 (Box 4)
  - Editorial Advisory Board, Chairman's Files, 1963-1965 (Box 4)
  - Editorial Advisory Board, Chairman's Files, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Editorial Advisory Board, Correspondence, 1952-1957 (Box 4)
  - Editorial Advisory Board, Correspondence, 1970-1974 (Box 4)
  - Editorial Advisory Board, circa 1939-1952 (Box 4)
  - Editorial Advisory Board, 1950-1961 (Box 4)
  - Editorial Advisory Board, Retreat, 1985 February 9 (Box 4)
  - Editorial Advisory Board, South Atlantic Quarterly Correspondence, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Editorial Advisory Board, Special Meetings, 1987-1988 (Box 4)
  - Editorial Advisory Board, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Editorial Advisory Board, 1991 (Box 4)
- Editor Files, 1928-1975
  Primarily correspondence between Duke Press editors and authors of books or journal articles. The folders are arranged alphabetically by author's last name or by journal/article title. This series reflects day-to-day operations of the Press. The correspondence with authors concerns topics related to seeing the book through publication such as content, editorial style, financial issues (includes some contracts), photos and indexes. Of particular note are the correspondence of the Hispanic American Historical Review, a folder detailing the origins of the publication of the Ecological Monographs journal at Duke and correspondence between the Press and editors of Frank C. Brown's Folklore Collection.
  - Blackburn, William B., 1944-1945 (One and Twenty) (Box 4)
  - Cahoon, John B., 1940-1967 (Formulating X-Ray Technics) (Box 4)
  - Davis, Helen Miller, 1950-1952 (Constitutions, Treaties, Electoral Laws of States in the Near and Middle East) (Box 4)
  - DeConde, Alexander, 1956-1958 (Isolation and Security) (Box 4)
  - DeConde, Alexander, 1956-1967 (Entangling Alliances and The Secretary of State) (Box 4)
  - Durden, Robert F., 1953-1975 (James Shepherd Pike: Republicanism and the American Negro, 1850-1882) (Box 4)
  - Durden, Robert F., 1960-1962 (Reconstruction Bonds and 20th Century Politics: SD v NC) (Box 4)
  - Hendricks, W.C., 1943-1944 (Bundle of Troubles and Other Tarheel Tales) (Box 4)
  - Hubbell, Jay B., 1952-1959 (The South in American Literature) (Box 4)
  - American Literature (journal), 1950-1958, Hubbell and Gohdes, eds. (Box 4)
  - American Literature (journal), 1954-1968, C. Gohdes, ed. (Box 4)
  - Ecological Monographs (journal), 1928-1959 (Box 4)
  - Ecology (journal), 1947-1963 (Box 4)
  - Hispanic American Historical Review (journal), 1953-1954, C. Griffin, ed. (Box 4)
  - Hispanic American Historical Review (journal), 1954, L. Hanke, ed. (Box 5)
  - Hispanic American Historical Review (journal), 1955, L. Hanke, ed. (Box 5)
  - Hispanic American Historical Review (journal), 1956-1960, L. Hanke, ed. (Box 5)
  - Hispanic American Historical Review (journal), 1956-1963, L. Hanke and D. Worcester, eds. (Box 5)
  - Southern Association Quarterly (journal), 1947-1949 (Box 5)
  - Kuznets, Moore and Spengler, 1955-1963 (Economic Growth: Brazil, India, Japan) (Box 5)
  - Leary, Lewis, 1946-1955 (Articles on American Literature) (Box 5)
  - Leary, Lewis, 1950-1951 (The Literary Career of Nathaniel Tucker) (Box 5)
  - Macdonald, Allan Houston, 1955-1972 (Richard Hovey, Man and Craftsman) (Box 5)
  - Mansergh, Nicholas, 1958 (Commonwealth Perspectives) (Box 5)
  - Tilley, Nannie M., 1947 (Guide to the Manuscript Collections in the Duke University Library) (Box 5)
  - White, Newman I., 1947-1951 (Frank C. Brown's Folklore) (Box 5)
  - White, Newman I., circa 1951-1952 (Frank C. Brown's Folklore) (Box 5)
  - White, Newman I., circa 1952-1957 folder one (Frank C. Brown's Folklore) (Box 5)
  - White, Newman I., circa 1952-1957 folder two (Frank C. Brown's Folklore) (Box 5)
  - Woodress, James L., 1952-1957 (Dissertations on American Literature/Howells and Italy) (Box 5)
  - Inquiries/Surveys, 1946-1947 (Box 5)
  - Inquiries/Surveys, 1948-1949 (Box 5)
  - Monthly Book Sale reports, 1952-1958 (Box 5)
  - Monthly Book Sale reports, 1959-1961 (Box 5)
  - Reports (including Annual Reports), 1932-1950 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence w/ Seeman Printery Inc., 1946-1949 (Box 5)
- Author Files, 1933-1965
  This series consists of correspondence with authors and publicity material related to the publication of individual books. Includes reviews, requests for review copies, lists of who should receive review copies, and correspondence with authors regarding publicity efforts. Mainly correspondence of the publicity director.
  - Acomb, Frances, 1948-1950 (Anglophobia in France, 1763-1789) (Box 6)
  - Bevington, Merle, 1952-1953 (Matthew Arnold's England and the Italian Question) (Box 6)
  - Blackburn, William, 1945-1952 (One and Twenty) (Box 6)
  - Blackburn, William, 1958-1959 (Joseph Conrad) (Box 6)
  - Blomquist, Hugo L., 1948-1950 (A Manual of the Grasses of North Carolina) (Box 6)
  - Boyd, William Kenneth, 1939-1951 (Historical Papers of Trinity College Historical Society) (Box 6)
  - Bradway, John S., 1945-1955 (Duke Legal Aid Clinic Handbook) (Box 6)
  - Brinkley, R. Florence, 1955-1957 (Coleridge on the 17th Century) (Box 6)
  - Cahoon, John B., 1957-1965 (Formulating X-Ray Technics) (Box 6)
  - Cartwright, W.H. and W.B. Hamilton, 1953 (Duke Centennial Conference On Teacher Training) (Box 6)
  - Chaffin, Nora B., 1947-1962 (Trinity College) (Box 6)
  - Clyde, Paul Hibbert, 1940-1942 (U.S. Policy Toward China) (Box 6)
  - Cole, Taylor, 1949-1952 (The Canadian Bureaucracy) (Box 6)
  - Crowell, John Franklin, 1938-1939 (Personal Recollections) (Box 6)
  - Davis, Thomas B., 1953-1955 (Carlos De Alvear) (Box 6)
  - Dowd, Jerome, 1938-1939 (Life of Braxton Craven) (Box 6)
  - Elliott, George Roy, 1951-1952 (Scourge and Minister) (Box 6)
  - Elliott, George Roy, 1952-1956 (Flaming Minister) (Box 6)
  - Ellwood, Charles A., 1933-1939 (Methods in Sociology) (Box 6)
  - Gohdes, Clarence and R.G. Silver, 1948-1950 folder one (Faint Clews and Indirections) (Box 6)
  - Gohdes, Clarence and R.G. Silver, 1948-1950 folder two (Faint Clews and Indirections), (Material for Circular and Jacket) (Box 6)
  - Hamilton, William B., 1952-1953 (50 Years of South Atlantic Quarterly) (Box 6)
  - Hamilton, William B., 1954-1955 (Anglo-American Law on the Frontier) (Box 6)
  - Hendricks, W.C., 1944-1945 (Bundle of Troubles) (Box 6)
  - Hubbell, Jay, 1941-1955 (The South in American Literature) (Box 6)
  - Judd, C.H. and others, 1939-1941 (A Century of Social Thought) (Box 6)
  - Lemkin, Raphael and McDermott, 1939-1940 (Polish Penal Code of 1932) (Box 6)
  - Lobonov-Rostovsky, Andrew, 1943-1950 (Russia and Europe) (Box 6)
  - London, Fritz, 1958 (Superfluids) (Box 6)
  - Mabry, William A., 1940-1943 (The Negro in North Carolina Politics Since Reconstruction) (Box 6)
  - McDougall, William, 1935-1937 (Religion and the Sciences of Life) (Box 6)
  - Parker, Harold T., 1943-1946 (Three Napoleonic Battles) (Box 6)
  - Pearse, A.S., 1937-1941 (Migrations of Animals from Sea to Land) (Box 6)
  - Robert, Joseph Clark, 1938-1939 (The Tobacco Kingdom) (Box 6)
  - Roper, Daniel C., 1941-1943 (50 Years of Public Life) (Box 6)
  - Sydnor, Charles S., 1938-1940 (Gentleman of the Old Natchez Region) (Box 6)
  - Tilley, Nannie, 1944-1948 (Guide to Manuscript Collections in the Duke University Library) (Box 6)
  - White, Newman I., and others, 1951-1955 (Frank C. Brown's Folklore) (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 1949-1956 (Box 6)
- Subject Files, 1942-1976
  Arranged alphabetically by subject, this series includes advertisements for publications, annual reports and correspondence from Ashbel Brice to President Knight, agendas, correspondence, and memoranda for meetings of the Southern University Presses.
  Also included is correspondence showing how inquiries about manuscript publication was handled during the 1940s and 1950s. There are also files on manuscripts possible, mansucripts unlikely, manuscripts rejected, and permission to quote from articles or books. This material has been sampled and around 20% retained.
  - Activities/Reports, 1961-1962 (Box 7)
  - Advertisements, circa 1963-1964 (A-R) (Box 7)
  - Advertisements, circa 1963-1964 (S-Z) (Box 7)
  - Lilly Endowment Research Series advertisements, circa 1964-1965 (Box 7)
  - American Book Publishers Council, Inc., 1961-1968 (Box 7)
  - Congressional Research Service (A. Brice), 1971-1975 (Box 7)
  - Law and Contemporary Problems, 1976 (Box 7)
  - Manuscript Inquiries, 1945-1947 (sample) (Box 7)
  - Manuscript Inquiries, 1946-1947 (Box 7)
  - Manuscript Inquiries, 1947-1949 (sample) (Box 7)
  - Manuscripts possible, 1951-1956 (sample) (Box 7)
  - Manuscripts received in office, 1945-1947 (sample) (Box 7)
  - Manuscripts received, 1952-1954 (sample) (Box 7)
  - Manuscripts rejected, 1942-1943 (sample) (Box 7)
  - Manuscripts rejected, 1953-1956 (sample) (Box 7)
  - Manuscripts unlikely, 1952-1956 (sample) (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous subjects (identified), 1968-1974 (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous subjects, 1974-1975 (Box 7)
  - Permissions (to quote, etc.), 1953-1956 (sample) (Box 7)
  - Reports, correspondence- Brice to President Knight, 1963-1969 (folder 1) (Box 7)
  - Reports, correspondence- Brice to President Knight, 1963-1969 (folder 2) (Box 7)
  - Southern University Presses- meetings, 1971-1972 (Box 7)
  - Southern University Presses- meetings, 1968-1970 (Box 7)
- Financial Records, 1926-1968
  This series includes detailed financial information, primarily annual reports, showing income and expenses for a given fiscal year. The material is often broken down between books and journals and occasionally documents how well individual books did also.
  - Financial Records, 1951-1952 (Box 7)
  - Financial Records, 1953-1954 (Box 7)
  - Financial Records, 1954-1955 (Box 7)
  - Financial Records, 1955-1956 (Box 7)
  - Financial Records, 1956-1957 (Box 7)
  - Financial Records, 1957-1958 (Box 7)
  - Financial Records, 1958-1959 (Box 7)
  - Financial Records, 1959-1960 (Box 7)
  - Financial Records, 1960-1961 (Box 7)
  - Financial Records, 1961-1962 (Box 7)
  - Financial Records, 1962-1963 (Box 7)
  - Financial Records, 1963-1964 (Box 7)
  - Financial Records, 1964-1965 (yearly book sales report) (Box 7)
  - Financial Records, 1956-1966(yearly book sales report) (Box 7)
  - Financial Records, 1966-1967 (yearly book sales report) (Box 7)
  - Financial Records, undated (Box 7)
  - Financial Records, estimates on never published manuscripts, 1961 (Box 7)
  - Financial Records, Printing Lists, 1959-1965 (Box 7)
  - Financial Records, Printing Lists, 1966-1968 (Box 7)
  - Financial Records, Income/Sales reports, 1956-1960 (graphs) (Box 7)
  - Financial Records, 1959-1960 audit (Box 7)
  - Financial Records, Sale reports, 1958 July-1962 February (Box 7)
  - Financial Records, miscellaneous (Box 8 (oversized material))
  - Financial Records, 1926/1927-1939/1940 (Box 8 (oversized material))
  - Detailed Financial Statements, 1959-1960 (Box 8 (oversized material))
  - Detailed Financial Statements, 1958-1959 (Box 8 (oversized material))
  - Detailed Financial Statements, 1957-1958 (two folders) (Box 8 (oversized material))
  - Detailed Financial Statements, 1956-1957 (Box 8 (oversized material))
- Catalogs, 1929-1989
  This series contains announcements, catalogs and trade lists advertising upcoming and current publications by Duke University Press.
  - Catalogs, Announcements, 1959 (Box 9)
  - Catalogs, Announcements, 1960-1969 (Box 9)
  - Catalogs, Announcements, 1970-1979 (Box 9)
  - Catalogs, Announcements, 1980-1989 (Box 9)
  - Catalogs, Announcements, undated (Box 9)
  - Duke University Press Catalogues, 1926-1959 (Box 9)
  - Duke University Press Catalogues and Trade Lists, 1960-1964 (Box 9)
  - Duke University Press Catalogues and Trade Lists, 1965-1969 (Box 9)
  - Duke University Press Catalogues and Trade Lists, 1970-1979 (Box 9)
  - Duke University Press Catalogues and Trade Lists, 1980-undated (Box 9)
  - Duke University Press Catalogues and Trade Lists, 1987-1989 (Box 9)
  - Catalogs, Journals (Box 9)
  - Catalogs, Trade Lists, 1924-1959 (Box 9)
- Association of American University Presses, 1948-1957
  The Association of American University Presses is a professional organization whose membership consists of University presses or publishers. The material relates to Duke University Press' membership to the AAUP and includes correspondence, memoranda, annual meeting minutes, questionnaires and a survey.
  - Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the Association of American University Presses, 1948 June 21-22 (Box 9)
  - Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the Association of American University Presses, 1949 May 9-11 (Box 9)
  - Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the Association of American University Presses, 1950 May 7-9 (Box 9)
  - Minutes of the 21st Anniversary Meeting of the Association of American University Presses, 1952 June 15-17 (Box 9)
  - Minutes of the 22nd Annual Meeting of the Association of American University Presses, 1953 April 12-14 (Box 9)
  - Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the Association of American University Presses, 1954 May 2-4 (Box 9)
  - Minutes of the 24th Annual Meeting of the Association of American University Presses, 1955 July 18-20 (Box 9)
  - Minutes of the 26th Annual Meeting of the Association of American University Presses, 1957 May 5-7 (Box 9)
  - Survey of University Presses, 1948-1949 (Box 9)
  - Survey of University Presses, 1948-1951 (Box 9)
  - Association of American University Presses, 1949-1950 (Box 9)
  - Association of American University Presses, 1951-1952 (Box 9)
  - Association of American University Presses, 1951-1952 (Box 9)
  - Association of American University Presses, 1952 (Box 9)
  - Association of American University Presses, 1953 (Box 9)
  - Association of American University Presses, 1954-1955 (Box 9)
- Oversize
  This series contains an account book which lists all expenditures and revenue for Duke University Press between 1925-1946. This box is located on-site.
  - Duke University Press Account Book, 1925-1946 (Box 10)
- Carlyle Letters, 1812-1856, (11 boxes)